Guide to the Carl L. Withers Manuscript Collection RISM.MC.1
New York University Archives
- Series V. Photographs, 1947-1950
  - Subseries B. Trinidad (Box 6)
    - Group 2
      - [Woman stands outside gated window], undated (Box 6, Object T-2 - 26)
      - [Ornately designed door], undated (Box 6, Object T-2 - 27)
      - [View of a gated living compound], undated (Box 6, Object T-2 - 28)
      - [Distant view of town with tower], undated (Box 6, Object T-2 - 29)
    - Group 3
      - [View of houses along a road], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 1)
      - [Young girl sits in a window], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 2)
      - [Cemetery], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 3)
      - [Another view of cemetery], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 4)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 5)
      - [Pack mules in the street], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 6)
      - [Houses on a cobblestone street], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 7)
      - [Another view of street], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 8)
      - [Young boy sitting by bamboo fence], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 9)
      - [Young girl with pail leans against brick wall], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 10a)
      - [Young boy with a tire; family members stand in doorway], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 10b)
      - [Another view of house and cobblestone street], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 11)
      - [Building with "Ford" sign], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 12)
      - [Urban street scene], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 13)
      - [Urban street scene], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 14)
      - [House under construction], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 15)
      - [Woman in front of gated door], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 16)
      - [Children outside and inside, talk through a gated window], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 17)
      - [Man in cowboy hat leaves building], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 18)
      - [Roasted pig being carved up], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 19)
      - [Young boys stand around roast pig - see above], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 20)
      - [Man with a wheelbarrow], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 21)
      - [A group of boys, one with a basket on his head], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 22)
      - [Three boys play in the street], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 23)
      - [Vendor with flags and trinkets], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 24)
      - [Man on a horse], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 25)
      - [Boy wearing hats for sale], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 26)
      - [Elderly woman stands in doorway], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 27)
      - [Group stands in doorway], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 28)
      - [Cemetery with three crosses], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 29)
      - [Men enter building in cemetery], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 30)
      - [Man with baskets of food], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 31)
      - [Men fixing street light], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 32)
      - [Children walk past men on horses], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 33)
      - [Different view of T-3 - 33], undated (Box 6, Object T-3 - 34)
    - Group 4
      - [Another view of cemetery - see T-3 - 29, T-3 - 30, undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 1)
      - [People gather around refreshment stand], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 2)
      - [Cobblestone street with tower in the distance], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 3)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 4)
      - [Young woman, dressed to go out, poses for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 5)
      - [Houses along a dirt road], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 6)
      - [People peer out of a barred window], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 7)
      - [Man and boy outside of house], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 8)
      - [Boy walking past house], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 9)
      - [Young boys playing a game], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 10)
      - [Child standing in doorway], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 11)
      - [Another view of boys at play], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 12)
      - [Children emerge from house to play], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 13)
      - [Young boy with dog at his feet stands in doorway], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 14)
        See also oversized photos
      - [Dog in above photo - out of focus], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 15)
      - [View of town architecture], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 16)
      - [View of bamboo fencing around house], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 17)
      - [Note on back: Slaughter house, Trinidad], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 18)
      - [Man walks toward building], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 19)
      - [View of back street], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 20)
      - [Boy stands in front of house], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 21)
      - [Two men, one with a caged bird, stand by bamboo fence], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 22)
      - [Same man in T-4-22 holding caged bird], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 23)
      - [Distant view of boy standing near building], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 24)
      - [Two boys play a game with pebbles], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 25)
      - [Same boys in T-4-25 with other children], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 26)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 27)
      - [Three small children in a rural setting], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 28)
      - [Man talks with women through barred window], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 29)
      - [Elderly woman sits in doorway], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 30)
      - [View of town architecture - duplicate of T-4-16], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 31)
      - [Elderly residents talk on street], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 32)
      - [Another street view], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 33)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 34)
      - [Bird sits on top of birdcage], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 35)
      - [View of railroad plaza], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 36)
      - [Another view of same area], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 37)
      - [Boy sitting on a bench], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 38)
      - [Young boy in foregound; two young girls in background], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 39a)
      - [Small baby gazes at the camera], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 39b)
      - [Two children stand outside building with the sign "El Volcano"], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 40)
      - [Group of chilren outside same building in T-4-40], undated (Box 6, Object T-4 - 41)
    - Group 5
      C. Withers' note: ("Trip to Tope de Collantes + man with fish")
      - [Thatch-covered dwelling], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 1)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 2)
      - [Men and horses outside building with partial view of sign that reads "Cristal"], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 3)
      - [Young boy with hills in the background], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 4)
      - [Building with ornately designed balcony], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 5A)
      - [Children stand on porch; sign partially reads "cigarros"], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 5B)
      - [Boy gazes at the camera; man stands in truck carrying goods], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 6A)
      - [Men on horses gather in front of building], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 6B)
      - [Distant view of buildings and hills], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 7)
      - [Child peers over fence from hilltop home], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 8)
      - [Family of child in T-5 - 8], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 9)
      - [Family of child in T-5 - 8], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 10)
      - [Individual with animal; building in background], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 11)
      - [Distant view of hillside with brushfire], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 12)
      - [Two young boys walk along a road; two men on horseback in the background], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 13)
      - Withers' note on back of photo: "Road from Tope de Collantes - they are returning from cockfight", undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 14)
      - Withers' note on back of photo: Aura in road - Tope [bird], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 15)
      - [Close-up view of lush foliage], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 16)
      - [Three boys sit on a stone fence], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 17)
      - [Scenic view of road with mountains in the distance], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 18)
      - [Man carrying a large fish], undated (Box 6, Object T-5 - 19)
    - Group 6
      - Withers note: boat at Casilda [Two men pulling boat to pier], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 1])
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 2])
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 3])
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 4])
      - [Group of adults and children], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 5])
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6-6])
      - [Partial view of chair inside doorway], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6-7])
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 8])
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 9])
      - [Children stand inside gated window or door], undated (Box 6, Object [T-6 - 10])
      - Unlabelled Havana photos (Box 6)
  - Subseries C. Baracoa (Box 6)
    - Group 1
      - [Young boys and teens pose for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object B1 - 1)
      - [Man riding a horse], undated (Box 6, Object B1 - 2)
      - [Boy and girl stand by a fence], undated (Box 6, Object B1 - 3)
      - [Children pose by a veranda], undated (Box 6, Object B1 - 4)
      - [Two boys sit in front of a house], undated (Box 6, Object B-1-5)
      - [Man walks with a tray on his head], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 6)
      - [Street scene], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 7)
      - [Houses along a road], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 8)
      - [Children kneeling and boy on bicycle pose for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 9)
      - [Street scene with hills in the background], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 10)
      - [House with posts in front], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 11)
      - [Man and woman walking along side of building with posts], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 12)
      - [Men, women and children walking in the street], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 13)
      - [Two boys, one balancing a carton of milk bottles on his head], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 14)
      - [Street scene with hillside structures in the background], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 15)
      - [Woman, book in hand, peers around a pillar], undated (Box 6, Object B-1 - 16)
    - Group 2
      - [Children playing with tire rim], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 1)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 2)
      - [Thatched houses along curved road], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 3)
      - [Man holding a small animal], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 4)
      - [Family posing in front of a home], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 5)
      - [Small child walking through cemetery], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 6)
      - [Another view of the cemetery], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 7)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 8)
      - [Woman leads a pig across road], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 9)
      - [Woman stands in doorway], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 10)
      - [Children playing rope], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 11)
      - [Children pose for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 12)
      - [Group stands in the distant background], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 13)
      - [Benches in outdoor plaza; a man leads mule train], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 14)
      - [A child plays on the steps of a building; man leads horses], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 15)
      - [Same view, different angle], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 16)
      - [Same view, at a distant angle], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 17)
      - [View of a plaza with trees], undated (Box 6, Object B-2 - 18)
    - Group 3
      - [Young girl and woman pose with elderly man], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 1)
      - [Plaza with tent or canopy], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 2)
      - [Children and man holding a pack mule], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 3)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 4)
      - [Outdoor scene, unclear], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 5)
      - [Scenic view of the shore], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 6)
      - [People walking on hilly road], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 7)
      - [People at vendor stand], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 8)
      - [Two men stand by a bus], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 - 9)
      - [One of the individuals in B-3-9 in back of bus], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 -10)
      - [Rural scene depicting coconut tree], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 -11)
      - [Young girl in front of house], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 -12)
      - [Woodworker], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 -13)
      - [View of a road; automobile in background], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 -14)
      - [Woman and young girl walking along the road; automobile in background], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 -15)
      - [Same road in photo B-3-7; horse and rider in the background], undated (Box 6, Object B-3 -16)
    - Group 4
      - [Family photo], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 1)
      - [Young boy from family in B-4-1 poses for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 2)
      - [Young girl from family in B-4-1 poses for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 3)
      - [Parents featured in B-4-1 pose with baby], undated (Box 6, Object B-4-4)
      - [Young man in street scene; houses in background], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 5)
      - [Closer view of young man in B-4-5], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 6)
      - [Young boy poses for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 7)
      - [Group of young men at far left; a church in the background], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 8)
      - [Same scene in B-4-8 at a different angle], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 9)
      - [Group of young boys and men pose for the camera], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 10)
      - [Same group in B-4-10 with additional people], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 11)
      - [Boys playing in the street; church in background], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 12)
      - [Street scene], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 13)
      - [Same scene in B-4-13, different angle], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 14)
      - [Same scene in B-4-13 with young girls in school uniform], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 15)
      - [Same scene in B-4-15], undated (Box 6, Object B-4 - 16)
    - Group 5
      - [Two men in a boxing ring], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 1)
      - [Observers at stadium], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 2)
      - [Same view as B-5-2], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 -3)
      - [Street scene], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 4)
      - [Children pose for camera], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 5)
      - [A church], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 6)
      - [Two women walk along road], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 7)
      - [Scenic coastal view], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 8)
      - [Street scene], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 9)
      - [Same street scene, different view], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 10)
      - [Same street scene, different view], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 11)
      - [Boat on the river, mountains in background], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 12)
      - [Boy walking along street], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 13)
      - [Street scene, church in background], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 14)
      - [Children playing outside house], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 15)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object B-5 - 16)
        Empty envelope "Baracoa Mixed Angel in Cemetery" [See Baracoa 1]
  - Subseries D. Camaguey - N.Y. (Box 6)
    - Group 1 (Carlers Rico)
      - [Urban street scene], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 1)
      - [House in foreground, city landscape in background], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 2)
      - [Urban street scene; Esso gas station sign], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 3)
      - [Boys and men pose for the camera], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 4)
      - [Men stand in front of building], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 5)
      - [Roof of the Carlos Rico Hotel Plaza, young boy with a parrot], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 6)
      - [two young men pose; towering structure visible in the background], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 7)
      - [Cuban street scene], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 8)
      - [Cuban landscape], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 9)
      - [Union Square?], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 10)
      - [Same area, different view], May 1948 (Box 6, Object C-1 - 11)
    - Group 2 [some negatives missing]
      - [Elderly man with walking stick], undated (Box 6, Object C-2 - 1)
      - [Street scene with trolley cars and automobiles], undated (Box 6, Object C-2 - 2)
      - [Courtyard with overturned pots], undated (Box 6, Object C-2 - 3)
      - [Man in a horse driven wagon], undated (Box 6, Object C-2 - 4)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-2 - 5)
      - [House in rural scene; large pot on the right], undated (Box 6, Object C-2 - 6)
    - Santiago De Cuba - Baracoa
      [Some negatives missing]
      - [Courtyard with well], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 7)
      - [Young girl crosses road to refreshment stand], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 8)
      - [Street scene with sign "Valla La Caridad"; church structure in background], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 9)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 10)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 11)
      - [A group of men in wide-brimmed hats], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 12)
      - [Young people in a open plaza], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 1)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 2)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 3)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 4)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 5)
      - [Scenic view of bay; island and mountains in the background], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 6)
      - [Three young men pose stand by bricks], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 7)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 8)
      - [Group in plaza; statue visible in the background], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 9)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 10)
      - Group 3
        - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3- 11)
        - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3- 12)
        - [Urban street scene; street signs on building read "Social" and "Esso"], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 13)
        - [Urban street scene; sign reads "Farmacia"], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 14)
        - [Man pulls a cart across the street], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 15)
        - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-3 - 16)
    - Group 4 [Out of focus]
      - [Urban street scene], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 1)
      - [Man stands at open window; sign reads "La Opera"], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 2)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 3)
      - [Children buying "Helado" or ice cream], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 4)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 5)
      - Doorway and sidewalk, undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 6)
      - Urban street scene, undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 7)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 8)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 9)
      - [Houses in foreground; city landscape in the background], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 10)
      - [Store sign reads "Guarina"], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 11)
    - Group 4
      - [Young men stand near fruit stand], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 12)
      - [Same scene, different angle], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 13)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 14)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 15)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-4 - 16)
    - Group 5
      - [Campaign signs read "Varona"], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 1)
      - [Same view, different angle], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 2)
      - [Urban street scene, church or cathedral in the background], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 3)
      - [Street scene], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 4)
      - [A church, partial image of a sign], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 5)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 6)
      - [Street scene, sign unclear], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 7)
      - [Same scene as above], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 8)
      - [View of city street], undated (Box 6, Object C-5 - 9)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C5 - 10)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C5 - 11)
      - [Individuals walking toward house, sign unclear], undated (Box 6, Object C5 - 12)
      - [View from inside a tent], undated (Box 6, Object C5 - 13)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C5 - 14)
      - [Individuals in a field, mountains in background], undated (Box 6, Object C5 - 15)
      - [Missing], undated (Box 6, Object C5 - 16)
    - Group 6 [Camaguey Duplicates]
      - [Three young men pose for camera; architectural details visible], undated (Box 6, Object C-6-1)
      - [Rural area with palm trees; house visible], undated (Box 6, Object C-6-2)
      - [Small child holding packages] (Box 6, Object C-6-3)
      - [Backyard in rural area; a well is visible] (Box 6, Object C-6-4)
    - Group 7 [Camaguey], undates (Box 6)
    - Group 8 [San Spiritus], undated (Box 6)
    - Group 9 [Santiago], undated (Box 6)
  - Subseries E: Scanned images of photos and unidentified photos
    - Mayajigua Scans (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
    - Trinidad, Baracoa, Camaguey-NYC Scans (Box 7, Folder 6-8)
    - Unidentified photos, undated (Box 11, Folder 1-13)
- Series VI. Unpublished Manuscripts
  Scope and Content Note
  2.0 linear feet, arranged numerically. This series consists of several unpublished manuscripts that represent the compilation of folklore collected by Carl Withers in Cuba. The manuscripts are written in Spanish but extensively annotated in English. In his bequest to RISM, (see Appendix) Withers describes the manuscripts as follows: 1) the Manolo Manuscript, an "autobiographical and descriptive document, based on the life of Manuel Picabea, a hired informant." The original Manolo Manuscript consisted of 1,525 pages, but missing pages have been indicated in brackets. Indexed notes are also included. Withers' bequest also includes The Life of Manolo (242 pages) and The World of Manolo (1016 pages). These manuscripts were shorter versions of the Manolo Manuscript edited by Luis Ratinoff between 1958 and 1959. A fourth manuscript, The World of A Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception, consists of four unnumbered sections. Researchers are asked to use preservation copies in boxes 15-17.
  - The Manolo Manuscript [original], 1948-03-1951-08 (Box 8)
    pp. 1 - 999 [Note: pp. 70 - 227 missing]
  - The Life of Manolo, The World of Manolo, The World of A Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception [empty], 1958 - 1959, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    [original copy]
  - Notes from Luis Rene Escobar [pp. 1 - 69], 1948 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Notes from Luis Rene Escobar[pp. 70 - 158], 1948 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - The World of a Cuban Nobody, undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - A Study in Social Perception, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - The World of a Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - The World of a Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - The World of a Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - The World of a Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - The World of a Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - The World of a Cuban Nobody: A Study in Social Perception, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - The Manolo Manuscript pp. 1 - 30 [Copies], Mar 1948 - Apr 1948, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - The Manolo Manuscript pp. 31 - 69, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - The Manolo Manuscript pp. 70 - 227 [Missing], undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The Manolo Manuscript pp. 228 - 289, Jul 1948 - Aug 1948 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - The Manolo Manuscript pp. 290 - 357, Jul 1948 - Aug 1948 (Box 15, Folder 5)